<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amber Nash</title>
    <description>Full Stack Web Developer
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 20:42:22 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 20:42:22 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Graduating Bootcamp: What Next?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image featured&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/work-harder.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TLDR&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-arrow-circle-right&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; You can’t learn everything, so be strategic&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-arrow-circle-right&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Don’t add on new tech unless it’s going to pay-off&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-arrow-circle-right&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Be confident in your primary language&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-arrow-circle-right&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Come up with a schedule to keep yourself accountable&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-arrow-circle-right&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Join a coding community – because you’ll code better and possibly get a job&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;congrats-grad&quot;&gt;Congrats Grad!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You survived! It’s been long days and longer nights. Sometimes your brain felt like a sieve – losing countless invaluable concepts and secrets – as you desperately tried to shovel everything back in. The fear of not being able to keep up was ever looming. By the time graduation hit, you and everyone in your program were exhausted and relieved. But, after you finished celebrating, that’s when you realized you were on your own. The training wheels had come off, and you were supposed to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-34075407&quot;&gt;MacGyver&lt;/a&gt; yourself into a full-time job as a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since graduating from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.devbootcamp.com&quot;&gt;Dev Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; this past March, I find myself in MacGyver mode. My Bootcamp did a great job in stressing the importance of studying/building/networking immediately post-graduation. But, like many of my cohort, that didn’t stop me from flailing around trying to get myself oriented. What language(s) should I focus on? How much time should I spend applying to jobs? Networking, that’s a thing I need to do immediately, right? OMG ALGORITHMS?!?!?!?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get real, &lt;strong&gt;you will not be able to learn everything.&lt;/strong&gt; You’re on a race to add expertise and new skills to your resume to make yourself more marketable. The more marketable you are, the faster you find a job. If you’re like me, getting hired soon rather than later is key (Money… you have to pay your bills with it). So, how do you tackle this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slow down.&lt;/strong&gt; Time management is the biggest obstacle. Think of the time between your graduation and your first job as sacred. That’s when you get to build yourself up before venturing into the “real world.” So, with that mind-set, don’t try and cram everything in your head. Be strategic about what languages/tech you add on to your existing knowledge. If you think it will make the difference between multiple recruiters calling you for an interview or not, it’s worth your time. If it doesn’t add to your marketability, bookmark it if it interests you, but if you’re actively job seeking there’s bigger fish to fry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take a look at several jobs that interest you, and figure out what the common tech stack is.&lt;/strong&gt; If a language pops up again and again, find a free workshop, buy a book, or sign up for an e-course. But, don’t think that you have to learn every language under the sun. Better to be secure in your primary language and make advances in a few others than spread yourself too thin and have nothing to show for it. Knowing a lot about a lot of things is great, but if you can’t solve a simple coding challenge in your primary language, knowing that obscure fact about {insert new-fangled language here} isn’t going to save the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a calendar and come up with a daily or weekly schedule.&lt;/strong&gt; The more you pretend this self-study is your full-time job, the better you’ll be at accomplishing your tasks. Even if you veer off from your schedule, keeping one and checking in with yourself will give you accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get some friends!&lt;/strong&gt; Hopefully, you connected with your Bootcamp cohort. If not, find a community of other programmers. There are endless reasons to do this but I’ll list a few for the highly anti-social: get help with bugs, learn new tricks from your new friends, build projects with people (looks good on the resume), networking &lt;strong&gt;(people will literally give you jobs if you show up places… show up!).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are my top recommendations for how to get yourself oriented post-graduation. I’ll get more in-depth on some of this in future posts. &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 07:36:23 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/graduated-what-next.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/graduated-what-next.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
